<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://janke.im/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://janke.im/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-07-14T07:19:02+00:00</updated><id>https://janke.im/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>TODO </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 17</title><link href="https://janke.im/blog/2025/WRaIS-17/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 17"/><published>2025-07-13T11:11:11+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-13T11:11:11+00:00</updated><id>https://janke.im/blog/2025/WRaIS-17</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://janke.im/blog/2025/WRaIS-17/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello Everyone to this Issue of Worthwhile Reads &amp; Interesting Stuff! Let’s get straight into it.</p> <h3 id="llms--ai">LLMs &amp; AI</h3> <ul> <li><a href="https://developers.googleblog.com/en/introducing-gemma-3n-developer-guide/">https://developers.googleblog.com/en/introducing-gemma-3n-developer-guide/</a> – Introducing Gemma 3n: the new Google LLM with improved efficiency and reasoning, and a detailed dev‑guide for integrating it into your stack.</li> <li><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09985">https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09985</a> – V‑JEPA 2: Self‑Supervised Video Models Enable Understanding, Prediction and Planning – presents a model for video that self‑supervises to predict future frames and plan tasks.</li> <li><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44376989">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44376989</a> – OpenAI charges by the minute, so speed up your audio – discussion highlights how per‑minute billing of OpenAI audio APIs pushes users to optimize for speed.</li> <li><a href="https://worksonmymachine.substack.com/p/mcp-an-accidentally-universal-plugin">https://worksonmymachine.substack.com/p/mcp-an-accidentally-universal-plugin</a> – MCP: An (Accidentally) Universal Plugin System – explores a simple plugin architecture that surprisingly adapts across platforms and languages.</li> <li><a href="https://blog.mozilla.ai/wasm-agents-ai-agents-running-in-your-browser/">https://blog.mozilla.ai/wasm-agents-ai-agents-running-in-your-browser/</a> – Wasm‑agents: AI agents running in your browser – Mozilla shows how to run lightweight AI agents entirely client‑side via WebAssembly.</li> <li><a href="https://huggingface.co/blog/smollm3">https://huggingface.co/blog/smollm3</a> – SmolLM3: smol, multilingual, long‑context reasoner – Lightweight multilingual LLM with extended context capacity, aiming for on‑device reasoning.</li> </ul> <h3 id="programming--development">Programming &amp; Development</h3> <ul> <li><a href="https://ordep.dev/posts/writing-code-was-never-the-bottleneck">https://ordep.dev/posts/writing-code-was-never-the-bottleneck</a> – Writing Code Was Never The Bottleneck – argues that communication, architecture, and alignment are the true constraints, not code.</li> </ul> <h3 id="security--other">Security &amp; Other</h3> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/linux/new-linux-udisks-flaw-lets-attackers-get-root-on-major-linux-distros/">https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/linux/new-linux-udisks-flaw-lets-attackers-get-root-on-major-linux-distros/</a> – New Linux udisks flaw lets attackers get root on major Linux distros – critical vulnerability in udisks can be exploited to escalate privileges to root.</li> <li><a href="https://trufflesecurity.com/blog/guest-post-how-i-scanned-all-of-github-s-oops-commits-for-leaked-secrets">https://trufflesecurity.com/blog/guest-post-how-i-scanned-all-of-github-s-oops-commits-for-leaked-secrets</a> – How I Scanned all of GitHub’s “Oops Commits” for Leaked Secrets – walkthrough of scanning public commits for inadvertently exposed API keys and credentials.</li> <li><a href="https://www.media.mit.edu/projects/your-brain-on-chatgpt/overview/">https://www.media.mit.edu/projects/your-brain-on-chatgpt/overview/</a> – Your Brain on ChatGPT – MIT Media Lab explores cognitive effects of interacting with ChatGPT over time.</li> <li><a href="https://calvin.sh/blog/fed-lie/">https://calvin.sh/blog/fed-lie/</a> – The Fed says this is a cube of $1 million. They’re off by half a million. – Calvin Shan debunks the Fed’s visual estimate, showing the real volume is 50% larger than claimed.</li> </ul> <p>This was this week’s list of worthwhile reads and interesting stuff, thanks for reading!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="WRaIS"/><category term="WRaIS"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A curated roundup across AI/LLMs, development insights, security alerts, and thought‑provoking deep dives.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 16</title><link href="https://janke.im/blog/2025/WRaIS-16/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 16"/><published>2025-06-15T11:11:11+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-15T11:11:11+00:00</updated><id>https://janke.im/blog/2025/WRaIS-16</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://janke.im/blog/2025/WRaIS-16/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello Everyone to this Issue of Worthwhile Reads &amp; Interesting Stuff!<br/> Let’s get straight into it.</p> <h3 id="llms">LLMs</h3> <ul> <li><a href="https://codinginterviewsmadesimple.substack.com/p/fine-tuning-llms-is-a-huge-waste">Fine-Tuning LLMs is a Huge Waste of Time</a>: A strong critique arguing that for many applications, relying on prompt engineering or retrieval often trumps costly fine-tuning workflows.</li> <li><a href="https://mistral.ai/news/magistral">Announcing Magistral — the first reasoning model by Mistral AI</a>: Mistral introduces Magistral, designed to excel at chain-of-thought reasoning and logical problem-solving.</li> </ul> <h3 id="programming-and-development">Programming and Development</h3> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.elastic.co/search-labs/blog/spring-ai-elasticsearch-application">Spring AI and Elasticsearch as your vector database</a>: Explains how to integrate Spring AI with Elasticsearch for efficient vector searches and generative app development.</li> <li><a href="https://nx.dev/blog/practical-guide-effective-ai-coding">A Practical Guide on Effective AI Use - AI as Your Peer Programmer</a>: Guides developers on leveraging AI like a collaborative peer, focusing on prompt clarity, review, and iteration.</li> <li><a href="https://inside.java/2025/05/03/javaone-java-ai/">Java for AI</a>: Discusses how Java is evolving for AI use-cases, including native libraries, tool support, and AI dev trends at JavaOne.</li> <li><a href="https://foojay.io/today/how-to-send-prompts-in-bulk-with-spring-ai-and-java-virtual-threads/">How to send prompts in bulk with Spring AI and Java Virtual Threads</a>: Demonstrates batching prompts using virtual threads to scale AI tasks efficiently in Java.</li> <li><a href="https://foojay.io/today/what-is-rag-and-how-to-secure-it/">What is RAG, and How to Secure It</a>: Breaks down Retrieval Augmented Generation and outlines best practices to secure RAG-based applications.</li> </ul> <h3 id="other">Other</h3> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.zeropartydata.es/p/localhost-tracking-explained-it-could">“Localhost tracking” explained. It could cost Meta 32 billion</a>: Investigates Meta’s hidden tracking via local storage and privacy impacts that may spark major fines.</li> <li><a href="https://tylertringas.com/ai-legal/">How AI Saved My Company From a 2‑Year Litigation Nightmare</a>: A founder recounts how AI tools helped them analyze contracts, avoid legal pitfalls, and sidestep lengthy litigation.</li> <li><a href="https://bryanhogan.com/blog/korean-age">Why Koreans Ask What Year You Were Born</a>: Explains the Korean age system, how it influences social etiquette and why birth year questions carry cultural weight.</li> </ul> <p>This was this week’s list of worthwhile reads and interesting stuff, thanks for reading!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="WRaIS"/><category term="WRaIS"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Curated reads on LLMs, AI development, programming, and tech insights.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 15</title><link href="https://janke.im/blog/2025/WRaIS-15/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 15"/><published>2025-06-09T11:11:11+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-09T11:11:11+00:00</updated><id>https://janke.im/blog/2025/WRaIS-15</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://janke.im/blog/2025/WRaIS-15/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello Everyone to this Issue of Worthwhile Reads &amp; Interesting Stuff! Let’s get straight into it.</p> <h3 id="llms">LLMs</h3> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.slater.dev/accelerated-incompetence/">AI: Accelerated Incompetence</a> — A compelling critique of how large language models often enable confident output over correctness, accelerating poor decision-making.</li> <li><a href="https://culture.ghost.io/genai-is-our-polyester/">GenAI is Our Polyester</a> — Drawing parallels between synthetic fabric and synthetic intelligence, this piece explores GenAI as a cultural and economic artifact.</li> <li><a href="https://fly.io/blog/youre-all-nuts/">My AI Skeptic Friends Are All Nuts</a> — A sharp, humorous defense of LLMs’ utility despite their flaws, urging critics to ground their concerns in real-world use cases.</li> </ul> <h3 id="programming-and-development">Programming and Development</h3> <ul> <li><a href="https://invariantlabs.ai/blog/mcp-github-vulnerability">GitHub MCP Exploited: Accessing private repositories via MCP</a> — Details a now-patched vulnerability that allowed attackers to access private GitHub repositories through the MCP feature.</li> <li><a href="https://www.legitsecurity.com/blog/remote-prompt-injection-in-gitlab-duo">Remote Prompt Injection in GitLab Duo Leads to Source Code Theft</a> — A practical breakdown of how prompt injection in GitLab Duo could expose sensitive source code, raising urgent security concerns.</li> <li><a href="https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/the-pulse-134">Stack overflow is almost dead</a> — Examines the sharp decline in Stack Overflow activity, attributing it to AI tools, community fatigue, and changing dev habits.</li> </ul> <p>This was this week’s list of worthwhile reads and interesting stuff, thanks for reading!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="WRaIS"/><category term="WRaIS"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A fresh batch of thoughtful reads on AI, programming, and developer culture.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 14</title><link href="https://janke.im/blog/2025/WRaIS-14/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 14"/><published>2025-05-25T11:11:11+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-25T11:11:11+00:00</updated><id>https://janke.im/blog/2025/WRaIS-14</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://janke.im/blog/2025/WRaIS-14/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello Everyone to this Issue of Worthwhile Reads &amp; Interesting Stuff! Let’s get straight into it.</p> <h3 id="llms">LLMs</h3> <ul> <li> <p><a href="https://matthewsinclair.com/blog/0178-why-llm-powered-programming-is-more-mech-suit-than-artificial-human">LLM-powered tools amplify developer capabilities rather than replacing them</a>: This article argues that LLMs serve as augmentative tools, enhancing developers’ abilities rather than replacing them, akin to a mech suit enhancing human capabilities.</p> </li> <li> <p><a href="https://www.aisnakeoil.com/p/ai-as-normal-technology">AI as Normal Technology</a>: Explores the concept of AI becoming a standard, integrated part of technology, emphasizing its normalization in everyday tools and applications.</p> </li> </ul> <h3 id="programming-and-development">Programming and Development</h3> <ul> <li> <p><a href="https://inside.java/2025/04/03/javaone-stream-gatherers/">Stream Gatherers - Deep Dive with the Expert</a>: A comprehensive look into Java’s Stream Gatherers, discussing their implementation and benefits in stream processing.</p> </li> <li> <p><a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/rust-turns-10-how-a-broken-elevator-changed-software-forever/">Rust turns 10: How a broken elevator changed software forever</a>: Celebrating Rust’s 10th anniversary, this piece reflects on how a simple incident led to the creation of a language emphasizing safety and concurrency.</p> </li> </ul> <h3 id="other">Other</h3> <ul> <li><a href="https://lcamtuf.substack.com/p/decibels-are-ridiculous">Decibels are ridiculous</a>: An insightful critique on the decibel scale, highlighting its counterintuitive nature and the confusion it often causes.</li> </ul> <p>This was this week’s list of worthwhile reads and interesting stuff, thanks for reading!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="WRaIS"/><category term="WRaIS"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring the evolving role of LLMs in development, programming milestones, and curious insights from the world of sound.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 13</title><link href="https://janke.im/blog/2025/WRaIS-13/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 13"/><published>2025-04-21T11:11:11+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-21T11:11:11+00:00</updated><id>https://janke.im/blog/2025/WRaIS-13</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://janke.im/blog/2025/WRaIS-13/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello Everyone to this Issue of Worthwhile Reads &amp; Interesting Stuff! It has been a while, but let’s get straight into it.</p> <p><strong>LLMs</strong></p> <ul> <li><a href="https://ai.meta.com/blog/llama-4-multimodal-intelligence/">Llama 4 is released</a>: Meta releases Llama 4, a new multimodal model pushing the frontier of open AI research.</li> <li><a href="https://openai.com/index/introducing-o3-and-o4-mini/">Introducing o3 and o4-mini</a>: OpenAI introduces o3 and o4-mini models with enhanced performance and versatility.</li> <li><a href="https://notebooklm.google/">NotebookLM</a>: Google’s NotebookLM is now public—an AI tool to organize and interpret personal content.</li> <li><a href="https://machinelearning.apple.com/research/seedlm-compressing">SeedLM</a>: Apple’s SeedLM compresses LLMs into random seeds, boosting efficiency and storage.</li> <li><a href="https://www.anthropic.com/news/anthropic-education-report-how-university-students-use-claude">Anthropic Education Report</a>: Anthropic explores how university students use Claude for study, productivity, and insight.</li> </ul> <p><strong>Programming and Development</strong></p> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.gatesnotes.com/home/home-page-topic/reader/microsoft-original-source-code">Microsoft’s Original Source Code</a>: Microsoft releases early source code, offering a nostalgic dive into tech history.</li> <li><a href="https://corrode.dev/blog/pitfalls-of-safe-rust/">Pitfalls of Safe Rust</a>: A blog post explores where “safe” Rust can still trip you up unexpectedly.</li> <li><a href="https://yossarian.net/til/post/any-program-can-be-a-github-actions-shell/">Any program can be a GitHub Actions shell</a>: Discover how literally <em>any</em> program can be used as a GitHub Actions shell.</li> <li><a href="https://blog.codingconfessions.com/p/python-performance-why-if-not-list">Python Performance</a>: A deep dive into why <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">if not list</code> outperforms <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">len(list) == 0</code> in Python.</li> <li><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43700607">CVE program faces swift end</a>: DHS fails to renew the CVE program contract, putting vulnerability tracking at risk.</li> </ul> <p><strong>Other</strong></p> <ul> <li><a href="https://standardebooks.org/">Standard eBooks</a>: Standard eBooks offers beautiful, open-source alternatives to public domain literature.</li> <li><a href="https://www.privacyguides.org/articles/2025/04/11/encryption-is-not-a-crime/#the-arguments-given-to-break-encryption-make-no-sense">Encryption Is Not a Crime</a>: Privacy Guides challenges the narrative that encryption threatens public safety.</li> <li><a href="https://theconversation.com/a-weird-phrase-is-plaguing-scientific-papers-and-we-traced-it-back-to-a-glitch-in-ai-training-data-254463">A weird phrase is plaguing scientific papers</a>: Researchers trace a bizarre phrase in science papers to flawed AI training data.</li> </ul> <p>This was this week’s list of worthwhile reads and interesting stuff, thanks for reading!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="WRaIS"/><category term="WRaIS"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A roundup of the latest in LLMs, programming quirks, open-source revelations, digital rights, and curious AI artifacts.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 12</title><link href="https://janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-12/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 12"/><published>2024-10-27T11:11:11+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T11:11:11+00:00</updated><id>https://janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-12</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-12/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello Everyone to this Issue of Worthwhile Reads &amp; Interesting Stuff!<br/> Let’s get straight into it.</p> <h4 id="llms">LLMs</h4> <h5 id="ai-detectors-falsely-accuse-students-of-cheatingwith-big-consequences"><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2024-10-18/do-ai-detectors-work-students-face-false-cheating-accusations">AI Detectors Falsely Accuse Students of Cheating—With Big Consequences</a></h5> <p>Investigates the reliability of AI detectors in academic settings and the impact of false positives on students.</p> <h5 id="you-should-probably-pay-attention-to-tokenizers"><a href="https://cybernetist.com/2024/10/21/you-should-probably-pay-attention-to-tokenizers/">You Should Probably Pay Attention to Tokenizers</a></h5> <p>A guide on why tokenizers are crucial in LLM performance and accuracy.</p> <h4 id="programming-and-development">Programming and Development</h4> <h5 id="supercharge-your-java-applications-with-python-youtube"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F8GoDqTtSOE">Supercharge your Java Applications with Python (YouTube)</a></h5> <p>Learn how integrating Python with Java can enhance your applications with new capabilities.</p> <h5 id="five-ways-to-speed-up-your-maven-builds"><a href="https://gradle.com/blog/five-ways-to-speed-up-your-apache-maven-builds/">Five ways to speed up your Maven builds</a></h5> <p>Essential tips for optimizing Maven build times to improve productivity.</p> <h5 id="software-engineer-titles-have-almost-lost-all-their-meaning"><a href="https://www.trevorlasn.com/blog/software-engineer-titles-have-almost-lost-all-their-meaning">Software Engineer Titles Have (Almost) Lost All Their Meaning</a></h5> <p>An analysis of how inflated job titles are diluting the value of engineering roles.</p> <h4 id="other">Other</h4> <h5 id="largest-known-prime-number-2136279841-1"><a href="https://www.mersenne.org/primes/?press=M136279841">Largest Known Prime Number: 2<sup>136,279,841</sup>-1</a></h5> <p>Delve into the math world’s latest find—the largest known prime, boasting over 41 million digits.</p> <p>This was this week’s list of worthwhile reads and interesting stuff, thanks for reading!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="WRaIS"/><category term="WRaIS"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week’s highlights cover the nuances of AI detection, tips for faster builds, and groundbreaking mathematical discoveries.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 11</title><link href="https://janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-11/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 11"/><published>2024-10-06T11:11:11+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-06T11:11:11+00:00</updated><id>https://janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-11</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-11/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello Everyone to this Issue of Worthwhile Reads &amp; Interesting Stuff!<br/> Let’s get straight into it.</p> <h4 id="llms">LLMs</h4> <h5 id="llama-32-revolutionizing-edge-ai-and-vision-with-open-customizable-models"><a href="https://ai.meta.com/blog/llama-3-2-connect-2024-vision-edge-mobile-devices/">Llama 3.2: Revolutionizing edge AI and vision with open, customizable models</a></h5> <p>Discover how Meta’s Llama 3.2 brings AI vision capabilities to mobile and edge devices.</p> <h5 id="chatgpt-now-shows-you-its-thought-process"><a href="https://lifehacker.com/tech/chatgpt-now-shows-you-its-thought-process">ChatGPT Now Shows You Its Thought Process</a></h5> <p>ChatGPT gets an upgrade, now explaining its reasoning to users for greater transparency.</p> <h4 id="programming-and-development">Programming and Development</h4> <h5 id="stop-trying-to-be-right"><a href="https://pathtostaff.substack.com/p/stop-trying-to-be-right">Stop Trying To Be Right</a></h5> <p>A lesson on the importance of focusing on problem-solving over being correct in team environments.</p> <h5 id="filesfileexists-or-fileexists"><a href="https://www.yegor256.com/2024/07/07/checking-object-existence.html">Files.fileExists or file.exists?</a></h5> <p>Dive into a detailed discussion on the nuances of checking file existence in Java.</p> <h4 id="other">Other</h4> <h5 id="octopuses-seen-hunting-together-with-fish-in-rare-video--and-punching-fish-that-dont-cooperate"><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/science/science-news/octopuses-hunt-with-fish-punch-video-rcna171705">Octopuses seen hunting together with fish in rare video — and punching fish that don’t cooperate</a></h5> <p>A quirky yet fascinating look at how octopuses collaborate with fish during hunting—sometimes with punches.</p> <h5 id="sony-ubisoft-scandals-prompt-calif-ban-on-deceptive-sales-of-digital-goods"><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/09/sony-ubisoft-scandals-prompt-calif-ban-on-deceptive-sales-of-digital-goods/">Sony, Ubisoft scandals prompt Calif. ban on deceptive sales of digital goods</a></h5> <p>Learn how gaming industry scandals are shaping new consumer protection laws in California.</p> <h5 id="sports-betting-apps-are-even-more-toxic-than-you-thought"><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-09-27/sports-betting-apps-are-even-more-toxic-than-you-imagined">Sports Betting Apps Are Even More Toxic Than You Thought</a></h5> <p>An investigation reveals the darker side of sports betting apps and their impact on users.</p> <p>This was this week’s list of worthwhile reads and interesting stuff, thanks for reading!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="WRaIS"/><category term="WRaIS"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring the future of AI, thought-provoking development insights, and unexpected science stories.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recipe - Rice salad (Reissalat)</title><link href="https://janke.im/blog/2024/Recipe-Rice-salad/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recipe - Rice salad (Reissalat)"/><published>2024-10-01T13:12:04+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-01T13:12:04+00:00</updated><id>https://janke.im/blog/2024/Recipe-Rice-salad</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://janke.im/blog/2024/Recipe-Rice-salad/"><![CDATA[<p>I first start with the <a href="#German">German</a> version, followed by a translation into <a href="#English">English below</a>.</p> <h2 id="german">German</h2> <p>Meiner Meinung nach darf Reissalat eigentlich auf keiner Party fehlen, vor allem nicht diese Variante. Sie ist gehaltvoll, aber auch saumäßig lecker.</p> <h4 id="zutaten">Zutaten:</h4> <ul> <li>150g Reis</li> <li>150g Mayonaise</li> <li>1,5 EL Sohasoße</li> <li>1 EL Zucker</li> <li>1 Zwiebel</li> <li>Salz</li> <li>1-2 Paprikaschoten</li> <li>200g gekochter Schinken</li> <li>1 Dose Mandarinen</li> </ul> <h4 id="zubereitung">Zubereitung</h4> <p>Den Reis kochen und etwas abkühlen lassen. Dann alle Zutaten vermischen. Den Salat am besten etwas ziehen lassen, also am besten einen halben bis ganzen Tag vorher zubereiten.</p> <p>Dann den Reissalat genießen.</p> <h2 id="english">English</h2> <p>In my opinion, rice salad should never be missing from any party, especially this version. It’s rich, but also incredibly delicious.</p> <h4 id="ingredients">Ingredients:</h4> <ul> <li>150g rice</li> <li>150g mayonnaise</li> <li>1.5 tablespoons soy sauce</li> <li>1 tablespoon sugar</li> <li>1 onion</li> <li>salt</li> <li>1-2 bell peppers</li> <li>200g cooked ham</li> <li>1 can of mandarins</li> </ul> <p>Cook the rice and let it cool down a bit.<br/> Then, mix all the ingredients together.<br/> It’s best to let the salad sit for a while, so ideally, prepare it half a day to a full day in advance.</p> <p>Enjoy your rice salad at the next party!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="recipe"/><category term="recipe"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An amazing sidedish for every party]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recipe - Maultaschen</title><link href="https://janke.im/blog/2024/Recipe-Maultaschen/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recipe - Maultaschen"/><published>2024-10-01T13:12:03+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-01T13:12:03+00:00</updated><id>https://janke.im/blog/2024/Recipe-Maultaschen</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://janke.im/blog/2024/Recipe-Maultaschen/"><![CDATA[<p>I first start with the <a href="#German">German</a> version, followed by a translation into <a href="#English">English below</a>.</p> <h2 id="german">German</h2> <p>Maultaschen sind ein wahres schwäbisches Kulturgut und aus der schwäbischen Küche nicht wegzudenken. Das nachfolgende Gericht beschreibt aber nicht die klassischen schwäbischen Maultaschen, sondern die fränkische Variante, die mir meine (fränkische) Mutter beigebracht hat. Typisch dafür ist auch das Fehlen von genauen Zutatenmengen. Hier muss man mit etwas gefühl arbeiten.</p> <h4 id="zutaten">Zutaten:</h4> <ul> <li>Hackfleisch</li> <li>Tomatenmark</li> <li>Zwiebeln</li> <li>Salz, Pfeffer, Paprikapulver, Petersilie</li> <li>evtl. Milch/Sahne</li> <li>Brötchen</li> <li>Butter</li> <li>Nudelteig</li> </ul> <h4 id="zubereitung">Zubereitung</h4> <p>Hackfleisch anbraten, würzen mit Tomatenmark, Zwiebeln, Salz, Pfeffer, Paprikapulver, Petersilie, evtl. Milch/Sahne. Die Konsistenz muss dabei fest bleiben! Das ganze kalt werden lassen.</p> <p>Brötchen klein schneiden und in Butter anrösten. Dann in das Fleisch mengen.</p> <p>Nudelteig dünn ausrollen und in Quadrate schneiden. Füllung rein und über Eck kleben.</p> <p>In Wasser ca. 20 Minuten ziehen lassen.</p> <p>Die fränkischen Maultaschen genießen!</p> <h2 id="english">English</h2> <p>Maultaschen are a true cultural treasure of Swabia and are indispensable in Swabian cuisine. However, the following recipe is not for the classic Swabian Maultaschen but the Franconian version that my (Franconian) mother taught me. A typical feature is the lack of precise ingredient measurements, so you’ll have to work with a bit of intuition.</p> <h4 id="ingredients">Ingredients:</h4> <ul> <li>Ground meat</li> <li>Tomato paste</li> <li>Onions</li> <li>Salt, pepper, paprika powder, parsley</li> <li>Optional: milk/cream</li> <li>Bread rolls</li> <li>Butter</li> <li>Pasta dough</li> </ul> <h4 id="preparation">Preparation</h4> <p>Brown the ground meat and season with tomato paste, onions, salt, pepper, paprika powder, parsley, and optionally some milk or cream. The consistency must remain firm!<br/> Let the mixture cool down.</p> <p>Cut the bread rolls into small pieces and roast them in butter. Then mix them into the meat.</p> <p>Roll out the pasta dough thinly and cut it into squares. Add the filling and fold the squares diagonally, sealing the edges.</p> <p>Let them simmer in water for about 20 minutes.</p> <p>Enjoy your Franconian-style Maultaschen!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="recipe"/><category term="recipe"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The classic South-German dish]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recipe - Lentils and Spätzle (Linsen und Spätzle)</title><link href="https://janke.im/blog/2024/Recipe-Lentils-and-spaetzle/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recipe - Lentils and Spätzle (Linsen und Spätzle)"/><published>2024-10-01T13:12:02+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-01T13:12:02+00:00</updated><id>https://janke.im/blog/2024/Recipe-Lentils-and-spaetzle</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://janke.im/blog/2024/Recipe-Lentils-and-spaetzle/"><![CDATA[<p>I first start with the <a href="#German">German</a> version, followed by a translation into <a href="#English">English below</a>.</p> <h2 id="german">German</h2> <p>Ein klassisches Gericht sind Linsen und Spätzle, das man einfach immer essen kann.</p> <h4 id="zutaten-4-personen">Zutaten (4 Personen):</h4> <ul> <li>Spätzle (siehe <a href="https://janke.im/blog/2024/Recipe-Spaetzle/">Spätzlerezept</a>)</li> <li>300g Linsen</li> <li>30g Fett</li> <li>50g Mehl</li> <li>1 Zwiebel</li> <li>1-2 Esslöffel Essig</li> <li>Senf, Salz</li> <li>Saitenwürstchen</li> </ul> <h4 id="zubereitung">Zubereitung</h4> <p>Die Linsen weichkochen. Mit Fett, Mehl und der feingehackten Zwiebel eine dicke braune Mehlschwitze zubereiten und die Linsen dazugeben. Mit den übrigen Zutaten abschmecken. Die Würstchen heiß machen und mit den selbstgemachten Spätzle und den Linsen servieren und genießen</p> <h2 id="english">English</h2> <p>A classic dish, Linsen und Spätzle, is something you can always enjoy. This comforting combination of lentils, Spätzle, and sausages is perfect for any time of year!</p> <h4 id="ingredients-for-4-people">Ingredients (for 4 people):</h4> <ul> <li>Spätzle (see <a href="https://janke.im/blog/2024/Recipe-Spaetzle/">Spätzle Recipe</a>)</li> <li>300g lentils</li> <li>30g fat (for frying)</li> <li>50g flour</li> <li>1 onion</li> <li>1-2 tablespoons vinegar</li> <li>mustard, salt</li> <li>sausage (Saitenwürstchen)</li> </ul> <h4 id="preparation">Preparation</h4> <p>Cook the lentils until soft.<br/> Prepare a thick, brown roux using the fat, flour, and finely chopped onion, and then add the lentils.<br/> Season with the remaining ingredients to taste.<br/> Heat the sausages and serve them with the homemade Spätzle and the lentils.</p> <p>Enjoy your meal!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="recipe"/><category term="recipe"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The classic South-German (side) dish]]></summary></entry></feed>