<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="janke.im/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="janke.im/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-07-29T07:36:41+00:00</updated><id>janke.im/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>TODO </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 7</title><link href="janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-7/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 7"/><published>2024-07-28T11:11:11+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-28T11:11:11+00:00</updated><id>janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-7</id><content type="html" xml:base="janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-7/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello Everyone to this Issue of Worthwhile Reads &amp; Interesting Stuff! Let’s get straight into it.</p> <h4 id="llms">LLMs</h4> <h5 id="1-bit-llms-could-solve-ais-energy-demands"><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/1-bit-llm">1-bit LLMs Could Solve AI’s Energy Demands</a></h5> <p>1-bit LLMs offer a promising solution to reduce AI’s energy consumption significantly.</p> <h5 id="llmgraphtransformer-langchain"><a href="https://python.langchain.com/v0.1/docs/use_cases/graph/constructing/">LLMGraphTransformer (LangChain)</a></h5> <p>LangChain’s LLMGraphTransformer enables efficient construction and analysis of complex graphs.</p> <h5 id="ai-existential-risk-probabilities-are-too-unreliable-to-inform-policy"><a href="https://www.aisnakeoil.com/p/ai-existential-risk-probabilities">AI existential risk probabilities are too unreliable to inform policy</a></h5> <p>Discusses the challenges and uncertainties in using AI existential risk probabilities for policy-making.</p> <h4 id="programming-and-development">Programming and Development</h4> <h5 id="what-is-entropy"><a href="https://johncarlosbaez.wordpress.com/2024/07/20/what-is-entropy/">What is entropy?</a></h5> <p>A deep dive into the concept of entropy and its implications in various fields.</p> <h5 id="counting-bytes-faster-than-youd-think-possible"><a href="https://blog.mattstuchlik.com/2024/07/21/fastest-memory-read.html">Counting Bytes Faster Than You’d Think Possible</a></h5> <p>Explores advanced techniques for rapidly counting bytes and optimizing memory read operations.</p> <h5 id="study-finds-268-higher-failure-rates-for-agile-software-projects"><a href="https://www.theregister.com/2024/06/05/agile_failure_rates/">Study finds 268% higher failure rates for Agile software projects</a></h5> <p>Examines a study highlighting the surprisingly high failure rates of Agile software projects.</p> <h5 id="reverse-engineering-for-everyone"><a href="https://0xinfection.github.io/reversing/">Reverse Engineering for Everyone</a></h5> <p>An accessible guide to reverse engineering for beginners and enthusiasts alike.</p> <h5 id="java-compareto-method-natural-order-of-things"><a href="https://igorstechnoclub.com/java-compareto/">Java compareTo method: Natural Order Of Things</a></h5> <p>Insights into the Java compareTo method and its role in establishing natural ordering.</p> <h4 id="other">Other</h4> <h5 id="how-olympics-officials-try-to-catch-motor-doping"><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/motor-doping-cycling">How Olympics Officials Try to Catch “Motor Doping”</a></h5> <p>Details on the technology and strategies used to detect motor doping in cycling competitions.</p> <h5 id="micromouse-the-fastest-maze-solving-competition-on-earth"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZMQbHMgK2rw">Micromouse: The Fastest Maze-Solving Competition On Earth</a></h5> <p>A look into the exciting world of micromouse maze-solving competitions and their rapid problem-solving robots.</p> <h5 id="dungeons--dragons-taught-me-how-to-write-alt-text"><a href="https://ericwbailey.website/published/dungeons-and-dragons-taught-me-how-to-write-alt-text/">Dungeons &amp; Dragons taught me how to write alt text</a></h5> <p>Lessons from Dungeons &amp; Dragons on writing effective and descriptive alt text for images.</p> <p>This was this week’s list of worthwhile reads and interesting stuff, thanks for reading!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="WRaIS"/><category term="WRaIS"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Insights into LLMs, Programming, Development, and More!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 6</title><link href="janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-6/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 6"/><published>2024-07-21T11:11:11+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-21T11:11:11+00:00</updated><id>janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-6</id><content type="html" xml:base="janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-6/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello Everyone to this Issue of Worthwhile Reads &amp; Interesting Stuff! Let’s get straight into it.</p> <h4 id="llms">LLMs</h4> <h5 id="evaluation-of-retrieval-augmented-generation-a-survey"><a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2405.07437">Evaluation of Retrieval-Augmented Generation: A Survey</a></h5> <p>This survey paper provides a comprehensive evaluation of retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) systems. It reviews methodologies, metrics, and benchmarks used to assess the performance of RAG models, highlighting current challenges and future research directions.</p> <h5 id="the-engineers-guide-to-deep-learning"><a href="https://www.interdb.jp/dl/">The Engineer’s Guide To Deep Learning</a></h5> <p>A detailed guide aimed at engineers, covering the fundamental concepts and advanced techniques in deep learning. It includes practical insights and best practices for implementing and optimizing deep learning models in various applications.</p> <h5 id="gpt-4o-mini-advancing-cost-efficient-intelligence"><a href="https://openai.com/index/gpt-4o-mini-advancing-cost-efficient-intelligence/">GPT-4o mini: advancing cost-efficient intelligence</a></h5> <p>OpenAI introduces GPT-4o mini, a cost-efficient variant of the GPT-4 model. The article discusses its development, performance improvements, and the potential for making advanced AI more accessible and affordable for a wider range of users.</p> <h4 id="programming-and-development">Programming and Development</h4> <h5 id="agile-manifesto-co-author-blasts-failure-rates-report-talks-up-reimagining-project"><a href="https://www.theregister.com/2024/07/16/jon_kern/">Agile Manifesto co-author blasts failure rates report, talks up ‘reimagining’ project</a></h5> <p>Jon Kern, co-author of the Agile Manifesto, critiques reports on high failure rates in agile projects and advocates for reimagining agile methodologies. He emphasizes the need for adaptability and continuous improvement in project management practices.</p> <h5 id="java-virtual-threads-a-case-study-"><a href="https://www.infoq.com/articles/java-virtual-threads-a-case-study/">Java Virtual Threads: a Case Study </a></h5> <p>This case study explores the use of Java Virtual Threads in real-world applications. It examines their impact on performance, scalability, and resource management, providing practical examples and insights for developers considering their adoption.</p> <h5 id="introduction-to-bash-scripting-free-ebook"><a href="https://github.com/bobbyiliev/introduction-to-bash-scripting">Introduction to Bash Scripting (Free eBook)</a></h5> <p>A free eBook offering a beginner-friendly introduction to Bash scripting. It covers basic concepts, common commands, and practical examples, making it a valuable resource for those looking to automate tasks and improve their command-line skills.</p> <h5 id="treemap-in-java-a-must-know-data-structure"><a href="https://igorstechnoclub.com/java-treemap/">TreeMap in Java: A Must-Know Data Structure</a></h5> <p>An informative article on TreeMap, a vital data structure in Java. It explains its implementation, use cases, and advantages, highlighting why understanding TreeMap is essential for Java developers working with ordered data.</p> <h5 id="how-a-single-line-of-code-brought-down-a-billion-dollar-rocket"><a href="https://newsletter.techworld-with-milan.com/p/how-a-single-line-of-code-brought">How a Single Line of Code Brought Down a Billion Dollar Rocket</a></h5> <p>This article recounts how a single line of faulty code led to the failure of a billion-dollar rocket. It delves into the technical details of the incident, emphasizing the critical importance of code quality and thorough testing in high-stakes projects.</p> <p>This was this week’s list of worthwhile reads and itneresting stuff, thanks for reading!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="WRaIS"/><category term="WRaIS"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Evaluation of RAG, GPT-4o mini, Java Virtual Threads & co.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 5</title><link href="janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-5/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 5"/><published>2024-07-14T11:11:11+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-14T11:11:11+00:00</updated><id>janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-5/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello Everyone to this Issue of Worthwhile Reads &amp; Interesting Stuff! Let’s get straight into it.</p> <h4 id="llms">LLMs</h4> <h5 id="graphrag-analysis-part-1-how-indexing-elevates-knowledge-graph-performance-in-rag"><a href="https://aiencoder.substack.com/p/graphrag-analysis-part-1-how-indexing">GraphRAG Analysis, Part 1: How Indexing Elevates Knowledge Graph Performance in RAG</a></h5> <p>This article explores the impact of effective indexing on the performance of knowledge graphs in retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) systems. It highlights the importance of indexing techniques in enhancing the accuracy and efficiency of data retrieval.</p> <h4 id="programming-and-development">Programming and Development</h4> <h5 id="deep-ml-ml-code-exercises"><a href="https://www.deep-ml.com/">Deep-ML, ML code exercises</a></h5> <p>Deep-ML offers a comprehensive collection of machine learning code exercises designed to help practitioners enhance their coding skills. The platform provides hands-on practice with real-world ML problems, catering to various skill levels.</p> <h5 id="choosing-the-right-jdk-version-an-unofficial-guide"><a href="https://blogs.oracle.com/java/post/choosing-the-right-jdk-version">Choosing the Right JDK Version: An Unofficial Guide</a></h5> <p>This guide helps developers navigate the complexities of choosing the appropriate Java Development Kit (JDK) version. It covers considerations such as compatibility, performance, and new features, providing practical advice for making informed decisions.</p> <h4 id="other">Other</h4> <h5 id="reverse-engineering-ticketmasters-rotating-barcodes-safetix"><a href="https://conduition.io/coding/ticketmaster/">Reverse Engineering TicketMaster’s Rotating Barcodes (SafeTix)</a></h5> <p>An in-depth analysis of TicketMaster’s SafeTix rotating barcodes, detailing the reverse engineering process. This article examines the security mechanisms behind the technology and explores potential vulnerabilities and their implications.</p> <h5 id="childrens-daily-sugar-consumption-halved-just-a-year-after-tax-study-finds"><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jul/09/childrens-daily-sugar-consumption-halves-just-a-year-after-tax-study-finds">Children’s daily sugar consumption halved just a year after tax, study finds</a></h5> <p>A study reveals that children’s daily sugar consumption was reduced by half within a year following the implementation of a sugar tax. The article discusses the public health implications and the effectiveness of such fiscal measures in promoting healthier diets.</p> <h5 id="a-new-age-of-materials-is-dawning-for-everything-from-smartphones-to-missiles"><a href="https://archive.ph/caK9m">A New Age of Materials Is Dawning, for Everything From Smartphones to Missiles</a></h5> <p>This article highlights the advancements in material science that are revolutionizing various industries, from consumer electronics to defense. It discusses the development of new materials with enhanced properties, driving innovation and performance.</p> <h5 id="europes-new-ariane-6-rocket-powers-into-space"><a href="https://www.esa.int/Enabling_Support/Space_Transportation/Ariane/Europe_s_new_Ariane_6_rocket_powers_into_space">Europe’s new Ariane 6 rocket powers into space</a></h5> <p>Europe’s Ariane 6 rocket successfully launched, marking a significant milestone in space transportation. The article covers the rocket’s development, capabilities, and its role in future space missions, emphasizing its importance for Europe’s space industry.</p> <p>This was this week’s list of worthwhile reads and itneresting stuff, thanks for reading!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="WRaIS"/><category term="WRaIS"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Delving into GraphRAG, JDK, and TicketMaster]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 4</title><link href="janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-4/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 4"/><published>2024-07-07T09:09:09+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-07T09:09:09+00:00</updated><id>janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-4/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello Everyone to the fourth Issue of Worthwhile Reads &amp; Interesting Stuff! Let’s get straight into it.</p> <h4 id="llms--co">LLMs &amp; co.</h4> <h5 id="ai-agents-that-matter"><a href="https://www.aisnakeoil.com/p/new-paper-ai-agents-that-matter">AI agents that matter</a></h5> <p>The paper explores the significance of AI agents in real-world applications, focusing on their impact, effectiveness, and ethical considerations. It provides insights into designing AI systems that meaningfully contribute to society and address critical challenges.</p> <h5 id="advanced-rag-series">Advanced RAG Series</h5> <ol> <li> <p><a href="https://div.beehiiv.com/p/routing-query-construction">Routing and Query Construction</a> This article is the first in the Advanced RAG Series, detailing techniques for routing and constructing queries in retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) systems. It covers methods to optimize query formulation for improved information retrieval.</p> </li> <li> <p><a href="https://div.beehiiv.com/p/advanced-rag-series-indexing">Indexing</a> The second article in the Advanced RAG Series discusses indexing strategies for RAG systems. It explains how to effectively organize and manage data indexes to enhance the performance and accuracy of information retrieval processes.</p> </li> <li> <p><a href="https://div.beehiiv.com/p/advanced-rag-series-retrieval">Retrieval</a> This third installment in the Advanced RAG Series focuses on retrieval techniques. It explores methods to efficiently fetch relevant information from indexed data, emphasizing the importance of speed and precision in retrieval-augmented generation systems.</p> </li> <li> <p><a href="https://div.beehiiv.com/p/advanced-rag-series-generation-evaluation">Generation and Evaluation</a> The final article in the Advanced RAG Series covers generation and evaluation processes in RAG systems. It highlights strategies for generating coherent and contextually accurate responses and evaluating the system’s overall performance and reliability.</p> </li> </ol> <h4 id="programming-and-development">Programming and Development</h4> <h5 id="advanced-github-actions-techniques"><a href="https://medium.com/@denispalnitsky/github-actions-advanced-techniques-78f0905f2668">Advanced GitHub Actions Techniques</a></h5> <p>This article provides advanced techniques for using GitHub Actions, including complex workflows, custom actions, and integration with other tools. It aims to help developers automate and streamline their CI/CD processes effectively.</p> <h5 id="cache-is-king-a-guide-for-docker-layer-caching-in-github-actions"><a href="https://blacksmith.sh/blog/cache-is-king-a-guide-for-docker-layer-caching-in-github-actions">Cache is King: A guide for Docker layer caching in GitHub Actions</a></h5> <p>An in-depth guide on optimizing Docker layer caching within GitHub Actions. It covers best practices for caching strategies to speed up builds, reduce costs, and enhance the efficiency of continuous integration workflows.</p> <h5 id="java-annotated-monthly--july-2024"><a href="https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2024/07/java-annotated-monthly-july-2024/">Java Annotated Monthly – July 2024</a></h5> <p>The July 2024 edition of Java Annotated Monthly offers a roundup of the latest news, tutorials, and updates in the Java programming community. It includes insights into new features, best practices, and notable developments in the Java ecosystem.</p> <h4 id="other">Other</h4> <h5 id="should-this-be-a-map-or-500-maps"><a href="https://escapethealgorithm.substack.com/p/should-this-be-a-map-or-500-maps">Should this be a map or 500 maps?</a></h5> <p>This article explores the complexities of data visualization, specifically the decision-making process between using a single map or multiple maps to represent data. It discusses the pros and cons of each approach, providing guidance on effective visualization techniques.</p> <p>This was the fourth issue of WRaIS, thanks for reading!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="WRaIS"/><category term="WRaIS"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Delving into advanced RAG]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 3</title><link href="janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 3"/><published>2024-06-30T09:09:09+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-30T09:09:09+00:00</updated><id>janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-3/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello Everyone to the third Issue of Worthwhile Reads &amp; Interesting Stuff! This week is a bit shorter, but still quite interesting.</p> <h4 id="llms--co">LLMs &amp; co.</h4> <h5 id="llamattf-a-font-which-is-also-an-llm"><a href="https://fuglede.github.io/llama.ttf/">Llama.ttf: A font which is also an LLM</a></h5> <p>Llama.ttf is a unique integration of a font and a large language model (LLM), offering an innovative way to interact with AI through text rendering. This project demonstrates the creative potential of combining typographic design with machine learning technology.</p> <h5 id="detecting-hallucinations-in-large-language-models-using-semantic-entropy"><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-07421-0">Detecting hallucinations in large language models using semantic entropy</a></h5> <p>This article discusses a novel method to identify hallucinations in large language models (LLMs) using semantic entropy. The approach aims to enhance the reliability of LLMs by detecting and mitigating instances where the AI generates false or misleading information.</p> <h5 id="ai-scaling-myths"><a href="https://www.aisnakeoil.com/p/ai-scaling-myths">AI scaling myths</a></h5> <p>The article debunks common misconceptions about scaling AI systems. It argues that larger models do not necessarily equate to better performance, and emphasizes the importance of data quality, model architecture, and training processes in achieving effective AI solutions.</p> <h4 id="software-development">Software development</h4> <h5 id="open-source-eclipse-theia-ide-exits-beta-to-challenge-visual-studio-code"><a href="https://visualstudiomagazine.com/Articles/2024/06/27/eclipse-theia-ide.aspx">Open Source ‘Eclipse Theia IDE’ Exits Beta to Challenge Visual Studio Code</a></h5> <p>Eclipse Theia, an open-source Integrated Development Environment (IDE), has exited beta and aims to compete with Visual Studio Code. Theia offers flexibility and extensibility, appealing to developers seeking a customizable and robust coding environment.</p> <p>This was the third issue of WRaIS, thanks for reading! See you next week!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="WRaIS"/><category term="WRaIS"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Delving into a LLM font, hallucinations, and Eclipse Theia IDE]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 2</title><link href="janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 2"/><published>2024-06-24T09:09:09+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-24T09:09:09+00:00</updated><id>janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-2/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello Everyone to the second Issue of Worthwhile Reads &amp; Interesting Stuff!</p> <h4 id="llms--co">LLMs &amp; co.</h4> <h5 id="every-way-to-get-structured-output-from-llms"><a href="https://www.boundaryml.com/blog/structured-output-from-llms">Every Way To Get Structured Output From LLMs</a></h5> <p>Explore various methods to extract structured data from large language models (LLMs). Techniques include prompting strategies, fine-tuning, and leveraging external tools, enhancing the utility of LLMs in structured data applications.</p> <h5 id="google-gemini-tried-to-kill-me"><a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/ChatGPT/comments/1diljf2/google_gemini_tried_to_kill_me/">Google Gemini tried to kill me</a></h5> <p>A Reddit user shares a humorous and hyperbolic account of their interaction with Google Gemini, highlighting potential flaws and unexpected behaviors in the AI system. The story underscores the unpredictable nature of AI responses.</p> <h5 id="bertscore-explained-in-5-minutes-and-a-visual-walkthrough-for-vectorized-bertscore-to-evaluate-text-generation"><a href="https://medium.com/@abonia/bertscore-explained-in-5-minutes-0b98553bfb71">BERTScore Explained in 5 minutes</a> And <a href="https://pub.towardsai.net/visual-walkthrough-for-vectorized-bertscore-to-evaluate-text-generation-b9ed61e6fdfe">A Visual Walkthrough for Vectorized BERTScore to Evaluate Text Generation</a></h5> <p>BERTScore offers a method to evaluate text generation quality by comparing contextual embeddings from BERT models. The first article provides a quick and accessible explanation of how BERTScore works and its advantages over. The second article is a comprehensive guide to using Vectorized BERTScore for text generation evaluation. It includes visual aids to help understand the implementation process and advantages of this method in measuring text quality.</p> <h5 id="delving-into-chatgpt-usage-in-academic-writing-through-excess-vocabulary"><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.07016">Delving into ChatGPT usage in academic writing through excess vocabulary</a></h5> <p>An academic paper examining the use of ChatGPT in scholarly writing, focusing on the tendency to produce verbose content. The study analyzes the implications of this verbosity on academic integrity and writing quality.</p> <h4 id="software-development">Software development</h4> <h5 id="efficient-containers-with-spring-boot-3-java-21-virtual-threads-and-cds-youtube"><a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/java/comments/1dj139h/efficient_containers_with_spring_boot_3_java_21/">Efficient containers with Spring Boot 3, Java 21, Virtual Threads and CDS (YouTube)</a></h5> <p>A YouTube video tutorial on creating efficient containerized applications using Spring Boot 3, Java 21, Virtual Threads, and Class Data Sharing (CDS). The video covers best practices and performance optimizations for modern Java applications.</p> <h4 id="social">Social</h4> <h5 id="do-not-try-to-be-the-smartest-in-the-room-try-to-be-the-kindest"><a href="https://www.jorgegalindo.me/en/blog/posts/do-not-be-the-smartest-in-the-room-try-to-be-the-kindest">Do not try to be the smartest in the room; try to be the kindest.</a></h5> <p>This blog post advocates for kindness over intelligence in social and professional settings. It argues that fostering a supportive and empathetic environment leads to better collaboration, creativity, and overall success.</p> <h5 id="experts-vs-imitators"><a href="https://fs.blog/experts-vs-imitators/">Experts vs. Imitators</a></h5> <p>An insightful article distinguishing between true experts and those who merely imitate expertise. It discusses the characteristics that set genuine experts apart, such as deep understanding, continuous learning, and the ability to apply knowledge in novel ways.</p> <p>This was the second issue of WRaIS, thanks for reading! See you next week!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="WRaIS"/><category term="WRaIS"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Delving into LLM and social interaction]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 1</title><link href="janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Worthwhile Reads &amp;amp; Interesting Stuff 1"/><published>2024-06-17T09:09:09+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-17T09:09:09+00:00</updated><id>janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="janke.im/blog/2024/WRaIS-1/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello Everyone to the first Issue of Worthwhile Reads &amp; Interesting Stuff!</p> <p>In this (roughly weekly) series, I want to post links to articles that I think are worthwhile to read and to further stuff like projects, repositories, videos, and more that I think are interesting. This serves, first, as a private list for me to find things later and, second, for others with similar interests as filtered links.</p> <p>As my current interest revolve around research in software architecture, LLMs, knowledge graphs, as well as programming in general and in particular about Java with some Python and Rust, many links will likely contain these topics. Additionally, there might be some humorous material as well as some other general stuff (politics, sports, music, …), if it fits.</p> <p>The overall layout and format might also evolve over time to improve the overall experience.</p> <p>Without further ado, here is the first issue.</p> <h4 id="llms--co">LLMs &amp; co.</h4> <h5 id="llms-arent-just-trained-on-the-internet-anymore"><a href="https://allenpike.com/2024/llms-trained-on-internet">LLMs Aren’t Just “Trained On the Internet” Anymore</a></h5> <p>Large language models (LLMs) are evolving beyond training solely on internet data. Companies are incorporating proprietary datasets, domain-specific information, and real-time data to enhance model accuracy and relevance. This approach addresses issues like outdated or biased information and improves the models’ performance in specialized fields.</p> <h5 id="breaking-up-is-hard-to-do-chunking-in-rag-applications"><a href="https://stackoverflow.blog/2024/06/06/breaking-up-is-hard-to-do-chunking-in-rag-applications/">Breaking up is hard to do: Chunking in RAG applications</a></h5> <p>Chunking is crucial in retrieval-augmented generation applications for managing large documents and optimizing retrieval. Effective chunking strategies enhance model performance by ensuring relevant information is retrieved and used. The article discusses techniques for efficient chunking, improving overall system efficiency and accuracy in handling extensive datasets. This is a nice entry point for RAG.</p> <h5 id="better-rag-results-with-reciprocal-rank-fusion-and-hybrid-search"><a href="https://www.assembled.com/blog/better-rag-results-with-reciprocal-rank-fusion-and-hybrid-search">Better RAG results with Reciprocal Rank Fusion and Hybrid Search</a></h5> <p>Combining Reciprocal Rank Fusion (RRF) and Hybrid Search improves RAG systems by integrating multiple search strategies. This method enhances answer accuracy and relevance by leveraging the strengths of different retrieval techniques, leading to better performance in information retrieval tasks.</p> <h5 id="to-believe-or-not-to-believe-your-llm"><a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2406.02543">To Believe or Not to Believe Your LLM</a></h5> <p>This paper explores uncertainty quantification in LLMs, focusing on distinguishing between epistemic and aleatoric uncertainties. By deriving an information-theoretic metric, the authors provide a method to detect unreliable outputs, particularly hallucinations, in model responses. Experiments show the effectiveness of this approach in improving response reliability.</p> <h4 id="software-development">Software development</h4> <h5 id="conversation-in-forums-how-software-forum-posts-discuss-potential-development-insights"><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0164121224001535">Conversation in forums: How software forum posts discuss potential development insights</a></h5> <p>This research paper adresses discussion in software forum posts. One interesting aspect is their result that 98\% of user feedback is relevant to software requirements. Moreover, the forum posts contain contextual information that can be used to resolve issues.</p> <p>This was the first (short) issue of WRaIS! See you next week!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="WRaIS"/><category term="WRaIS"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[First Issue!]]></summary></entry></feed>